Rahul Upadhyay

B-25, Kaushik Enclave, Burari New Delhi - 110084

Contact No: - +91-9716187662

E-mail:- rahulupadhyay2014@gmail.com rahulupadhya@outlook.com

SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Profile

A result-oriented professional with + 6 years' experience in web application development & enhancement, service delivery and client relationship management.

Technical skill

₹ Technologies/Language - C#, MVC, ASP.Net, Ado.net, EF, Web Service, LinQ, WCF, API,

Angularis.

♦ Database Known - SQL Server 2012/2016.

API Integration - HDFC Payment Gateway API, Money transfer API,

SSO(Single Sign On), E-Com Express API, Mobile Recharge API (Pre-Paid, Postpaid).

Responsibilities

D1	1-1-1-1-1-1-1-1-1	C4	_1 :	1	1- !4 4
Develop	nign-duality	software	aesign	ana	architecture.

☐ Design, develop and implement new integration.

☐ Identify, prioritize and execute tasks in the software development life cycle.

☐ Perform validation and verification testing.

☐ Review and debug code.

☐ Collaborate with internal teams and vendors to fix and improve products.

□ Document development phases and monitor systems.

☐ Execute system development and maintenance activities.

Work Experience

Organization	Position	Duration					
1. HCL Technologies	Senior Software Engineer	02-Aug-2018 to Till Date					
2. Experis IT Pvt. Ltd	Software Developer	19-April-2017 to 01-Aug-2018					
Note: - Working as TP (contract base) in HCL Technologies							
3. Zeal Hi-Tech IT Pvt. Ltd	Software Developer	01-May-2015 to 18-April-2017					
4. MARCOM	Software Developer	12-May-2014 to 30-April-2015					
5. SunTec Web Services Pvt Ltd	Sr. Process Associates	01-Sep-2012 to 09-May-2014					

Projects

1. Project Title : Compensation Planner

Environment : VS-2015, MVC, Angular js, API

Database : SQL Server 2016 Web Script : JavaScript, JQuery.

Duration : Going Team Member : 7

Role : Development, Change Request

Project Detail : This project based on Offshore and Onsite Employee Salary and letter release logic.

2. Project Title : My Performance

Environment : VS-2015, MVC, Angular js, API

Database : SQL Server 2016

Team Member : 5

Role : Development

Project Detail : This project based on Employee appraisal process.

3. Project Title : Transfer Management System

Environment : VS-2015, MVC
Database : SQL Server 2016

Team Member : 2

Role : Development, Change Request

Project Details : This project based on Offshore and Onsite Employee Fitment.

4. Project Title : Kangra Herb

URL : <u>www.herbalhealthcare.co.in</u>
Environment : VS-2012, Entity Framework, LinQ

Database : SQL Server 2012

Team Member 5

Role : Development

Project Details : It is the MLM based project. Interested people can register to the site by paying a small amount 500. Once they are registered. They can invest amount by getting one of the plan. It will cause their MLM parents to be benefited. Project involves the modules like, Registration and validation, Wallet,

Binary, Referrer, Deposit, Payout, Pin Management and other MLM modules.

Academic Qualification

- 10th from CBSE.
- **†** 12th from CBSE.
- **BCA** (Bachelor of Computer Applications) from **IGNOU** with **First Division**.
- **MCA** (Masters of Computer Application) from **IGNOU** with **First Division**.

Date: -___/___/2019 (Signature)
Place: - New Delhi Rahul Upadhyay